Guide to the LeGrand Cannon Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
LeGrand Cannon collection
1938-1979
YCAL MSS 674
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.67
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of writings and correspondence by or relating to the American novelist LeGrand Cannon. Writings consist of autograph manuscript and typescript drafts of Look to the Mountain, Come Home at Even (also including proofs), and These are Some Stories about Old George Brown. Correspondents include Charles Beecher Hogan, Stephan Stearns, and Donald Wing.
Cannon, LeGrand, Jr., 1899-1979
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired by gift, 1943-1980.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
LeGrand Cannon
LeGrand Cannon Jr. (1899-1979, Yale College 1920), American novelist, author of Look to the Mountain.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings and correspondence by or relating to the American novelist LeGrand Cannon. Writings consist of autograph manuscript and typescript drafts of Look to the mountain, Come home at even (also including proofs), and These are some stories about old George Brown. Correspondents include C. Beecher Hogan, Stephan Stearns, and Donald Wing.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Writings, circa 1943-circa1979. II. Correspondence, 1938-1942.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Novelists, American -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Novelists -- United States -- 20th Century; Cannon, LeGrand, Jr., 1899-1979; Hogan, Charles Beecher, 1906-; Wing, Donald Goddard, 1904-1972; Stearns, Stephan
- Writings, circa 1942-circa 1979; Series I; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of drafts and proofs of three works by LeGrand Cannon: Look to the mountain, Come home at even, and These are some stories about old George Brown.
  - Look to the mountain, draft, autograph manuscript, circa 1942 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Look to the mountain, draft, autograph manuscript, circa 1942 (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
  - Look to the mountain, draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1943 (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
  - Come home at even, draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 13-14)
  - Come home at even, proofs, corrected, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
  - These are some stories about old George Brown, typescript and copy, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
- Correspondence, 1938-1942; Series II; 0.21; (1 box)
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Series II consists of three autograph letters, signed, by LeGrand Cannon.
  - Hogan, C. Beecher, 1942 May 14 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Stearns, Stephan, 1944 November 3 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Wing, Donald, 1938 December 6 (Box 5, Folder 21)